<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MinutesAndInformation>
	<Minutes date="10/13/2013" author="Ken">
	<item>ASGC 2013 Banquet and Meeting</item>
	<item>October 5, 2013, Saturday</item>
	<item>Hiroshi's Restaurant on Eastlake</item>
	<item>Meeting called to order by Vice President George Tsukamaki.</item>
	<item>Attendance:</item>
	<item>--15 members present - Bob, Bruce, Don, George, Harry, Howard, Jeff, Jin, Ken, Kiyo, Mel, Nate N, Nate O, Rich K, Takashi.</item>
	<item>Old Business:</item>
	<item>None.</item>
	<item>2. Motion to raise KP awards from $3.00 to $5.00.  12 against, 2 for, not passed.  KP award to remain at $3.00.</item>
	<item>New Business:</item>
	<item>1. Motion to "strongly" request more tournament up north.  Bruce will take on the request.</item>
	<item>Election of Officers for 2014 Season:</item>
	<item>1. Treasurer/Secretary: Ken volunteered for co-position with Rich Kirihara.</item>
	<item>2. Handicap Chairman: Jeff volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>3. Webmaster: Howard/Jeff accepted co-position.</item>
	<item>4. Tournament Chairman: Bruce volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>5. Awards Chairman: Don and Kiyo nominated for the position.  Kiyo voted in on a 10 to 5 vote. volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>6. Vice President: Jin and Nate O. nominated for the position. Jin voted in on a 9 to 3 vote.</item>
	<item>7. President:  Rich N. and Howard nominated for the position. Rich N. voted in on an 8 to 7 vote.</item>
	<item>Presentation of Golfer of the Year 2013:</item>
	<item>Vice-President George presented Rich N (absent) with the Golfer of the Year Award. Nate O. accepted for Rich N.</item>
	<item>Awards and Prizes:</item>
	<item>Rich K. conducted door prize activity with other various awards.</item>
	<item>Meeting adjourned shortly after.</item>
	<item>Minutes recorded by Ken.</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="10/13/2012" author="Ken">
	<item>ASGC 2012 Banquet and Meeting</item>
	<item>October 13, 2012, Saturday</item>
	<item>Angelo's in Bellevue</item>
	<item>Meeting called to order by President Duane Mayeda.</item>
	<item>Attendance:</item>
	<item>--18 members present</item>
	<item>Old Business:</item>
	<item>1. Agreed to have NWGA continue to make tee times and Bruce to continue as AS Golf tournament chairman.</item>
	<item>2. Motion to raise KP awards from $3.00 to $5.00.  12 against, 2 for, not passed.  KP award to remain at $3.00.</item>
	<item>New Business:</item>
	<item>None.</item>
	<item>Election of Officers for 2013 Season:</item>
	<item>1. Treasurer/Secretary: Ken volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>2. Handicap Chairman: Jeff volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>3. Webmaster: Howard Himeno accepted position via proxy (Ken).</item>
	<item>4. Tournament Chairman: Bruce volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>5. Awards Chairman: Rich Kirihara volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>6. Vice President: George volunteered for position.</item>
	<item>7. President:  Rich Nobuyama elected unanimously for position.</item>
	<item>Presentation of Golfer of the Year 2012:</item>
	<item>President Duane presented Rich Kirihara with the Golfer of the Year Award.</item>
	<item>Awards and Prizes:</item>
	<item>Allan conducted door prize activity with other various awards.</item>
	<item>Meeting adjourned shortly after.</item>
	<item>Minutes recorded by Ken.</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="10/01/2011" author="Ken">
<item>ASGC 2011 Banquet and Meeting</item>
<item>October 1, 2011, Saturday</item>
<item>Anthony's in Kirkland</item>
<item>Meeting called to order by President Takashi Tsukamaki at 7:15 pm.</item>
<item>Attendance:</item>
<item>--18 members present (Terry, Don, Allan F, Al H, Howard, Ralph, Bruce, Rich K, Duane, Bob, Jeff, Harry, Nate N,  Kiyo, Bill, Mun, Takashi, Ken)</item>
<item>--7 members not-present (Rik, Rich N, Roy, Nate O, Dan, George, Gary)</item>
<item>Old Business:</item>
<item>1. Motion to have NWHGA continue to make tee times and Bruce to continue as AS Golf tournament chairman.  Bruce volunteered to pay his dues.  Vote taken: 16 for, 0 against, 2 abstain.  Motion passed.</item>
<item>New Business:</item>
<item>1. Motion to allow new members to be eligible to win tournaments if they possess a GHIN handicap.  They will use their GHIN handicap for the first 3 tournaments played, then will use AS Golf handicap thereafter.  Vote taken: 16 for, 2 against.  Motion passed.</item>
<item>2. Motion brought up by Mun on limiting guests to only playing 3 tournaments with the club.  After discussion among members, motion was withdrawn.</item>
<item>Election of Officers for 2012 Season:</item>
<item>1. Treasurer/Secretary: Ken volunteered for position.</item>
<item>2. Handicap Chairman: Jeff volunteered for position.</item>
<item>3. Webmaster: Howard Himeno for position.</item>
<item>4. Tournament Chairman: Bruce volunteered for position.</item>
<item>5. Awards Chairman: Bill, Al H, Mun nominated.  Vote taken: Bill = 3, Al H = 14, Mun = 1.  Al H elected to position.</item>
<item>6. Vice President: Mun nominated.  Vote taken: Mun=16.  Mun elected to position.</item>
<item>7. President:  Duane, Allan F, Bill nominated.  Vote take: Duane = 9, Allan F = 8, Bill = 0.  Duane elected to position.</item>
<item>Presentation of Golfer of the Year 2011:</item>
<item>President Takashi presented Nate with the Golfer of the Year Award.</item>
<item>Awards and Prizes:</item>
<item>1. Harry conducted door prize activity.</item>
<item>2. Iron Man Award presented to Bruce, Mun, and Bill.</item>
<item>Meeting adjourned at 8:0pm.</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="10/02/2010" author="Dan">
<item>
02-Oct-10, Saturday
Ivars Salmon House on Lake Union
Seattle, WA
</item>
<item>
Meeting called to order by President Nate Nouchi at 8:16pm.
 </item>
<item>
Attendance:
--16 members present (Terry, Mel, Bruce, Rich K., Duane, Bob, Jeff, Rich N., Nate N., Roy, Nate O., Kiyo, Doyle, Mun, Dan, Takashi)
--5 members not-present (Don, Howard, Harry, George, Ken)
</item>
<item>
Rich Kirihara. passed out ASGC Officers History sheet (from 1988-), updated to 
include 2010 officers.
</item>
<item>
Old Business:
None.
</item>
<item>
New Business:
1. Sharing of Tee Times with Northwest Hawaiian Golf Association (NWHGA):
    --Discussion/Questions on scheduling of dates, payments, logistics, golf 
course selection, etc.
    --Mun Taketa pointed out that primary purpose is to share tee-times to 
ensure tournament reservations; details on logistics can be worked out later.  
NWHGA is volunteering to do the reservations, starting in October 2010.  Puget 
Sound GC members to help coordinate dates to minimize conflicts.
    --Mel Asato made motion for ASGC to share tee times with NWHGA.  Rich 
Kirihara seconded motion.  Vote taken: Y=14, N=0, Abstain=2.  Motion passed.
2. Two-Day Tournament scheduling: Takashi Tsukamaki made motion to have the ASGC 
Two-Day Tournament on two consecutive tournaments in the month of August, near 
the end of the season.  Motioned seconded.  Vote taken: Y=12, No=0, Abstain=4.  
Motion passed.
3. GIN Numbers: Mel Asato made comment that NWHGA has members pay annual $25 fee 
to maintain official GIN #'s.  It was noted that several ASGC members do not 
have official GIN #'s; however, since ASGC does not use GIN handicaps, it is not 
required to have one.  Mel noted that there could be an option for ASGC members 
to acquire GIN's through NWHGA if they wish to.  Discussion closed (no motion 
made).
</item>
<item>
Election of Officers for 2011 Season:
1. Treasurer/Secretary: Ken Yamabe nominated and elected to position.
2. Handicap Chairman: Jeff Nakasone volunteered for position.
3. Tournament Chairman: Bruce Kaneshiro nominated and elected to position.
4. Vice President: Terry Aoki and Harry Nishimoto nominated for position of Vice 
President.  Vote taken: Terry=13, Harry=3.  Terry elected to position.
5. President: Takashi Tsukamaki nominated and elected to position.
6. Awards Chairman: Roy Okamoto and Mun Taketa nominated for position of Awards 
Chairman. Vote taken: Roy=11, Mun=2. Roy elected to position.
7. Webmaster: Howard Himeno nominated and elected to position.
</item>
<item>
Presentation of Golfer of the Year 2010:
President Nate Nouchi presented Bruce Kaneshiro with the Golfer of the Year 
Award.
</item>
<item>
Awards and Prizes:
Awards Chairman Bob Motoyama presented 2 large prizes. Drawing held:
1. Roy Okamoto received golf bag.
2. Mun Taketa received golf cart.
3. All other members received gift bag.
4. Iron Man Award (members who participated in all tournaments) given to Bob 
Motoyama, Bruce Kaneshiro, and Mun Taketa.
</item>
<item>
New Members:
It was encouraged to be on the lookout for potential new members as we would 
like our club to grow.
</item>
<item>Meeting adjourned at 9:01pm.</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="10/11/2008" author="Ken">
		<item>The meeting was called to order by President, Mun Taketa at the Newport Bay restaurant in Kirkland.</item>
		<item>19 members were present.</item>
		<item>Ken Yamabe brought to the floor that there was a net loss this year.  It was noted that the green fees paid for the TC was $475 this year.  In 1993 it was $227.  The green fees have more than doubled but dues have gone from $80 to $125 in that same time period.</item>
		<item>Mel Asato put a motion on the table.  TC on rotation basis with next year TC being pulled from a hat.  Every year thereafter, chairman would be next member alphabetically.  If person did not want to be TC, they would pay a $100 fine and next member in line would take position.  TC would not have green fees paid for them.  Mun amended motion saying that volunteer would take rotation assignment.  Ken seconded motion.  Vote taken, 2 in favor.  Motion did not pass.</item>
		<item>Harry Nishimoto put a motion on the table.  TC would get paid $250 instead of all green fees.  Takashi amended motion to get TC's membership dues paid only.  Vote taken, 13 in favor, motion passed.</item>
		<item>Motion made to handle selection of TC, voted in, the same as in previous years.  Vote taken, 11 in favor, motion passed.</item>
		<item>Ken Yamabe mentioned that the Club now has its own credit card that will be used to pay for tournaments.  The credit card will earn 1% cash on purchases.  If Ken receives any document from IRS for earnings from this credit card, he will debit the club's account to cover the increase in taxes paid by him.</item>
		<item>Jeff Nakasone put a motion on the table to use the handicap index along with the courses slope rating to come up with a "Course Handicap" for each member playing the course.  This is how the USGA handles handicapping for tournaments.  Harry seconded the motion.  Vote taken, 13 in favor, motion passed.</item>
		<item>Don Chikuma elected to position of President, with 14 votes.</item>
		<item>Harry Nishimoto was voted in as next year's tournament chairman with a unanimous vote.</item>
		<item>Kiyo and Takashi nominated for position of Vice-President.  Vote taken, Kiyo 11, Takashi 4.  Kiyo Sawa elected to position of Vice-President.</item>
		<item>Jeff Nakasone volunteered for position of handicap chairman.</item>
		<item>Rich N and Rich K nominated for position of Awards Chairman.  Vote taken, Rich N 7, Rich K 1.  Rich Nobuyama elected to position of Awards Chairman.</item>
		<item>Ken declined position of Secretary/Treasurer.  Debbie Fraser nominated for position.  Vote taken, 8 in favor, 1 against.  Debbie Fraser elected to position of Secretary/Treasurer.  (See Addendum below)</item>
		<item>Howard Himeno volunteered for position of Webmaster.</item>
		<item>Dan and Bruce nominated for position of Tournament Chairman.  Vote taken, Dan 11, Bruce 7.  Dan Tamashiro elected to position of Tournament Chairman.</item>
		<item>Awards presentation conducted by Mel.</item>
		<item>Iron Man award given to Mun and Bruce.</item>
		<item>It was voted (13 yes) to change the payoff for the 36 hole tournament to $175, $125, and $75 respectively for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd place.</item>
		<item>Addendum: It was later agreed upon by Debbie and Ken that the Secretary/Treasurer position would be split.  Debbie would assume the Secretary responsibilities and Ken would take on the Treasurer responsibilities.</item>
		</Minutes>
		<Minutes date="10/20/2007" author="Ken">
		<item>
			The meeting was called to order by President, George Tsukamaki at Miyabi Japanese Restaurant in Tukwila.
		</item>
		<item>14 members were present.</item>
		<item>
			George brought up how "Winter Rules" were defined.  It was decided that if a ball is lying in the second cut of the fairway, it may be moved to the fairway provided it is moved no more than 6 inches and no nearer to the green.  "Winter Rules" does not apply to a ball in a hazard.
		</item>
		<item>
			It was voted (8 yes, 3 no) to have "Winter Rules" apply to all AS Golf tournaments.
		</item>
		<item>
			Nate Okinaka was voted in as a new member with a unanimous vote.
		</item>
		<item>
			It was voted to raise dues to $125.00.  With this raise in dues, it was agreed to raise tournament awards to $20, $15, and $10 for 1st, 2nd, and 3rd place finishes respectively.
		</item>
		<item>
			Iron man awards were distributed to Rich K., George, and Jeff.
		</item>
		<item>
			Harry Nishimoto was voted in as next year's tournament chairman with a unanimous vote.
		</item>
		<item>
			Howard Himeno, Ken Yamabe, and Jeff Nakasone volunteered for Webmaster, Secretary/Treasurer, and Handicap Chairman Positions respectively
		</item>
		<item>Mun Taketa was elected to position of President with a unanimous vote.</item>
		<item>Bruce Kaneshiro was elected to position of vice president by a vote of 8 to 6.</item>
		<item>Mel Asato was elected to position of Awards Chairman by a vote of 13 to 1.</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="10/7/2006" author="Ken">
		<item>
			The meeting was called to order by vice President Ralph
			Iboshi at Grazies in Bellevue.
		</item>
		<item>13 members were present.</item>
		<item>
			Howard Himeno, Ken Yamabe, and Jeff Nakasone volunteered for
			Webmaster, Secretary/Treasurer, and Handicap Chairman
			Positions respectively.
		</item>
		<item>
			Rich Kirihara was voted in as next year's tournament
			chairman with a 9 to 3 majority.
		</item>
		<item>
			George Tsukamaki reelected to position of President with a
			unanimous vote.
		</item>
		<item>
			Teri Aoki elected to position of vice president by a vote of
			7 to 1.
		</item>
		<item>
			Doyle Simmons volunteered for Awards Chairman position.
		</item>
		<item>
			It was agreed that club dues will now be required by the
			first of the year.
		</item>
		<item>
			It was agreed by all members present that the 5 door prizes
			would go to members present only.
		</item>
		<item>Iron Men awards distributed.</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="10/01/2005">
		<item>
			During member meeting at the 2004 banquet, it was brought to
			attention that the handicap was not "uncapped", but raised
			from 36 to 40. This was verified by meeting minutes taken by
			Rich Kirihara on Sept 2003. This cap will be applied from
			next season on.
		</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="03/01/2004">
		<item>
			Handicaps are now "uncapped", passed as a new AS Golf rule
			agreed upon by members at the last banquet meeting.
		</item>
	</Minutes>
	<Minutes date="04/08/2002" author="Jeff">
		<item>Handicaps are capped at 36, just like the USGA.</item>
		<item>
			It takes three club scores till a new member is qualified
			for tournament competition.
		</item>
		<item>
			Handicaps are for new members are 36 until established. This
			is for calculating adjusted scores.
		</item>
		<item>
			New members play with B-flight on KPs until their HDCP is
			established.
		</item>
	</Minutes>
</MinutesAndInformation>